<resources>
    <string name="app_name">AircraftsEncyclopedia</string>
    <string name="categories">Categories</string>


    <string name="slide_1_title">The easiest !</string>
    <string name="slide_1_desc">Welcome to the easiest and most enjoyable way to recognize aircraft.</string>

    <string name="slide_2_title">Brief and useful !</string>
    <string name="slide_2_desc">Varied information and clever categorization.</string>

    <string name="slide_3_title">Brief information !</string>
    <string name="slide_3_desc">Best description with photos in each model.</string>

    <string name="slide_4_title">Expert !</string>
    <string name="slide_4_desc">You will eventually become an aircraft expert.</string>

    <string name="skip">Skip</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="gotit">Got It</string>


    //Airbus
    <string name="general_explanation">General explanation</string>
    <string name="general_characteristics">General characteristics</string>
    <string name="airbusA300">The Airbus A300 is a wide-body twin engine jet airliner that was developed and manufactured by Airbus.  Formally announced in 1969 and first flying in October 1972, it holds the distinction of being the world\'s first twin-engined widebody airliner; it was also the first product of Airbus Industrie, a consortium of European aerospace manufacturers, now a subsidiary of Airbus.  The A300 can typically seat 266 passengers in a two-class layout, with a maximum range of 4,070 nautical miles (7,540 km) when fully loaded, depending on model.  Development of the A300 began during the 1960s as a European collaborative project between various aircraft manufacturers in the United Kingdom, France, and West Germany.</string>
    <string name="airbusA310">The Airbus A310 is a medium to long-range twin-engined wide-body jet airliner that was developed and manufactured by Airbus, then a consortium of European aerospace manufacturers.  It was the second airliner to be produced by the company, the first being the A300.  The A310 is a smaller derivative of the A300, which held the distinction of being the first twin-engined widebody airliner.  On 7 July 1978, Airbus decided to launch the A300B10 programme, which it had re-designated as the A310.  The A310 has been used by the armed forces of the following countries ↓↓↓  •Belgian Air Component •Royal Canadian Air Force •Egyptian Air Force •French Air Force •German Air Force •Royal Jordanian Air Force •Mongolian Air Force •Pakistan Air Force •Spanish Air Force •Royal Thai Air Force  By the end of production a total of 255 A310s had been ordered and delivered.</string>
    <string name="airbusA318">The Airbus A318 is the smallest member of the Airbus A320 family of short- to medium-range, narrow-body, commercial passenger twin-engine jet airliners manufactured by Airbus.  The A318 carries up to 132 passengers and has a maximum range of 5,700 km.  Final assembly of the aircraft took place in Hamburg,Germany.  The A318 entered service in July 2003 with Frontier Airlines.</string>
    <string name="airbusA319">The Airbus A319 is a member of the Airbus A320 family of short- to medium-range, narrow-body, commercial passenger twin-engine jet airliners manufactured by Airbus.  The A319 carries up to 160 passengers and has a maximum range of 6,900 km.  Final assembly of the aircraft takes place in Hamburg, Germany and Tianjin, China.  As of February 2018, a total of 1,469 Airbus A319 aircraft have been delivered, of which 1,448 are in service.</string>
    <string name="airbusA320">The Airbus A320 family consists of short- to medium-range, narrow-body, commercial passenger twin-engine jet airliners manufactured by Airbus.  Final assembly of the family takes place in Toulouse, France, and Hamburg, Germany.  The first member of the A320 family-of the A320-was launched in March 1984, first flew on 22 February 1987, and was first delivered in March 1988 to launch customer Air France.  As of 31 March 2018, a total of 8,074 Airbus A320-family aircraft have been delivered, of which 7,722 are in service.  In December 2010, Airbus announced a new generation of the A320 family, the A320neo (new engine option). The A320neo offers new, more efficient engines, combined with airframe improvements and the addition of winglets, named Sharklets by Airbus.</string>
    <string name="airbusA321">The Airbus A321 is a member of the Airbus A320 family of short- to medium-range, narrow-body, commercial passenger twin-engine jet airliners manufactured by Airbus. It was the first derivative of the baseline Airbus A320 aircraft, and carries up to 236 passengers with a maximum range of 5,900 km.  Final assembly of the aircraft takes place in Hamburg, Germany, or Mobile, Alabama. As of 31 December 2017, a total of 1,636 Airbus A321 aircraft have been delivered, of which 1,618 are in service.</string>
    <string name="airbusA330">The Airbus A330 is a medium-to long-range wide-body twin-engine jet airliner made by Airbus. Versions of the A330 have a range of 5,000 to 13,430 kilometers and can accommodate up to 335 passengers in a two-class layout or carry 70 tons of cargo.</string>
    <string name="airbusA340">The Airbus A340 is a long-range, four-engine, wide-body commercial passenger jet airliner that was developed and produced by the European aerospace company Airbus. The A340 was assembled in Toulouse, France. It seats up to 375 passengers in the standard variants and 440 in the stretched 600 series. Depending on the model, it has a range of 6,700 to 9,000 nautical miles (12,400 to 16,700 km; 7,700 to 10,400 mi).  Its distinguishing features are four high-bypass turbofan engines and three-bogie main landing gear. Launch customers Lufthansa and Air France placed the A340 into service in March 1993. The most common type was the A340-300 model, with 218 aircraft delivered. ‹Lufthansa› is the biggest operator of the A340, having acquired 59 aircraft.</string>
    <string name="airbusA350">The Airbus A350 XWB is a family of long-range, twin-engine wide-body jet airliners developed by European aerospace manufacturer Airbus. The A350 is the first Airbus aircraft with both fuselage and wing structures made primarily of carbon fiber reinforced polymer.  Its variants seat 280 to 366 passengers in typical three-class seating layouts.  The A350 is positioned to succeed the A340 and to compete with the Boeing 787 and 777.</string>
    <string name="airbusA380">The Airbus A380 is a double-deck, wide-body,four-engine jet airliner manufactured by European manufacturer Airbus. It is the world\'s largest passenger airliner, and the airports at which it operates have upgraded facilities to accommodate it.  The A380 made its first flight on 27 April 2005 and entered commercial service on 25 October 2007 with Singapore Airlines.  An improved version, the A380plus, is under development.  ‹Emirates› is the biggest A380 customer with 162 ordered of which 103 have been delivered.</string>


    //Antonov
    <string name="antonovA40">The Antonov A-40 Krylya Tanka (Russian: крылья танка, meaning tank wings),was a Soviet attempt to allow a tank to glide onto a battlefield after being towed aloft by an airplane, to support airborne forces or partisans.  A prototype was built and tested in 1942, but was found to be unworkable.  This vehicle is sometimes called the A-40T or KT.</string>
    <string name="antonovA11">The Antonov A-11 is a single-seat, high performance, all-metal sailplane built in the Soviet Union in the late 1950s. 150 were produced.</string>
    <string name="antonovA13">The Antonov A-13 was a Soviet aerobatic sailplane flown in the 1950s and 1960s. It was a small, single-seat, all-metal aircraft developed from the A-11which could optionally be fitted with that aircraft\'s longer-span wings. It was a mid-wing monoplane with a tadpole-like fuselage and a V-tail.In February 1962, an A-13 was fitted with a small turbojet engine to set a world airspeed record of 196 km/h (122 mph) for an aircraft weighing up to 500 kg. This jet-powered version was known as the An-13</string>
    <string name="antonov132">The Antonov/Taqnia An-132 is an improved version of the Antonov An-32 twin-engine turboprop military transport aircraft being developed jointly by Saudi Arabia and Ukraine</string>
    <string name="antonovA14">The Antonov An-14 Pchelka -Russian: «Пчелка», Little Bee- NATO reporting name Clod- is a Soviet utility aircraft which was first flown on 15 March 1958. It was a twin-engine light STOL utility transport, with two 300 hp Ivchenko AI-14RF radial piston engines. Serial production started in 1966, and about 300 examples were built by the time production ended in 1972. The An-14 failed to replace the more successful An-2 biplane, which was manufactured until 1990, (the An-2 is still manufactured on special order).</string>
    <string name="antonov140">The Antonov An-140 is a turboprop regional airliner, designed by the Ukrainian Antonov ASTC bureau as a successor to the Antonov An-24, with extended cargo capacity and the ability to use unprepared airstrips.</string>
    <string name="antonov148">The Antonov An-148 (Ukrainian: Антонов Ан-148) is a regional jet designed and built by Antonov of Ukraine. Until 2017, it was also built by Russia\'s Voronezh Aircraft Production Association.</string>
    <string name="antonov158">The Antonov An-158 is a stretched fuselage version of the aircraft, accommodating up to 100 passengers. Following a crash in February 2018, which is still under investigation, all An-148 and An-158 in Russia were grounded by the Russian Ministry of Transport.</string>
    <string name="antonov178">The Antonov An-178 (Ukrainian: Антонов Ан-178) is a short-range medium-airlift military transport aircraft designed by the Ukrainian Antonov company and based on the Antonov An-158 (An-148-200).  It was announced on 5 February 2010, rolled out on 16 April 2015 and the first flight was on 7 May 2015. The An-178 is proposed to replace outdated aircraft like the Antonov An-12, An-26 and An-32.</string>
    <string name="antonov12">The Antonov An-12 Russian: Антонов Ан-12- -NATO reporting name: Cub- is a four-engine turboprop transport aircraft designed in the Soviet Union. It is the military version of the Antonov An-10 and has many variants.</string>
    <string name="antonov10">The Antonov An-10 (Russian: Антонов Ан-10; NATO reporting name: Cat) was a four-engine turboprop passenger transport aircraft designed in the Soviet Union.</string>
    <string name="antonov124">The Antonov An-124 Russian (Ukrainian: Антонов Ан-124 Руслан) (NATO reporting name: Condor) is a strategic airlift jet aircraft. It was designed in the 1980s by the Antonov design bureau in the Ukrainian SSR, then part of the Soviet Union (USSR). Until the Boeing 747-8F, the An-124 was, for thirty years, the world\'s heaviest gross weight production cargo airplane and second heaviest operating cargo aircraft, behind the one-off Antonov An-225 (a greatly enlarged design based on the An-124).</string>
    <string name="antonov2">The Antonov An-2 is a Soviet mass-produced single-engine biplane utility/agricultural aircraft designed and manufactured by the Antonov Bureau beginning in 1946. The An-2 was designed as a utility aircraft for use in forestry and agriculture. The most common version is the An-2T 12-seater passenger aircraft.</string>
    <string name="antonov22">The Antonov An-22 Antei -Ukrainian: Ан-22 Антей- An-22 Antej -English Antheus- (NATO reporting name Cock) is a heavy military transport aircraft designed by the Antonov Design Bureau in the Soviet Union. Powered by four turboprop engines each driving a pair of contra-rotating propellers, the design was the first Soviet wide-body aircraft and remains the world\'s largest turboprop-powered aircraft to date. The An-22 first appeared publicly outside the Soviet Union at the 1965 Paris Air Show. Since then, the model has seen extensive use in major military and humanitarian airlifts for the Soviet Union.</string>
    <string name="antonov225">The Antonov An-225 Mriya  Ukrainian: Антонов Ан-225 Мрія, lit. \'dream\' or \'inspiration\', NATO reporting name: \'Cossack\' is a strategic airlift cargo aircraft that was designed by the Antonov Design Bureau in the Ukrainian SSR within the Soviet Union during the 1980s.</string>
    <string name="antonov24">The Antonov An-24 -(Russian/Ukrainian: Антонов Ан-24)- -(NATO reporting name: Coke)- is a 44-seat twin turboprop transport/passenger aircraft designed in 1957 in the Soviet Union by the Antonov Design Bureau and manufactured by Kiev, Irkutsk and Ulan-Ude Aviation Factories.</string>
    <string name="antonov26">The Antonov An-26 (NATO reporting name: Curl) is a twin-engine turboprop civilian and military transport aircraft, designed and produced in the Soviet Union from 1969 to 1986.</string>
    <string name="antonov28">The Antonov An-28 (NATO reporting name Cash) is a twin-engine light turboprop transport aircraft, developed from the Antonov An-14M. It was the winner of a competition against the Beriev Be-30, for use by Aeroflot as a short-range airliner. It first flew in 1969. A total of 191 were built and 16 remain in airline service as at August 2015.</string>
    <string name="antonov3">The Antonov An-3 is a Soviet (later Ukrainian and Russian) civil multipurpose and agricultural aircraft. It is essentially a turboprop-powered development of the An-2, designed to upgrade or replace it. The first example flew as early as May 13, 1980, but because of a lack of official interest in the project, work proceeded very slowly. Flight testing was not complete until 1991. It is one of the few turbine-powered biplane designs to date.</string>
    <string name="antonov30">The Antonov An-30 (NATO reporting name: Clank), is a development of the An-24 designed for aerial cartography.</string>
    <string name="antonov32">The Antonov An-32 (NATO reporting name: Cline) is a twin-engine turboprop military transport aircraft.</string>
    <string name="antonov38">The Antonov An-38 is a stretched and upgraded version of Antonov\'s earlier An-28. It is a twin-engine turboprop transport aircraft, designed by the Antonov Design Bureau in Kiev, Ukraine. Production is in Novosibirsk, Russia, but some crucial parts are also made in Ukraine and Belarus.</string>
    <string name="antonov50">The Antonov An-50 was a planned Soviet airliner with four turbojets. It was planned by Antonov in the first part of the 1970s. The aircraft was never built. The plans were complete in 1972, but nothing had been built. There was no prototype. It was planned to weigh 24600 kg gross, and it would have had a 490 km/h speed at 9400 m altitude.</string>
    <string name="antonov70">The Antonov An-70 (Ukrainian: Антонов Ан-70) is a four-engine medium-range transport aircraft, and the first aircraft to take flight powered only by prop fan engines.  It was developed in the late 1980s by the Antonov Design Bureau to replace the obsolete An-12 military transport aircraft.</string>
    <string name="antonov71">The Antonov An-71 (NATO reporting name: Madcap) was a Soviet AWACS aircraft intended for use with VVS-FA (Fighter Bomber) forces of the Soviet Air Force, developed from the An-72 transport. Only three prototypes were built before the program was cancelled.</string>
    <string name="antonov72">The Antonov An-72 (NATO reporting name: Coaler) is a Soviet/Ukrainian transport aircraft, developed by Antonov. It was designed as an STOL transport and intended as a replacement for the Antonov An-26, but variants have found success as commercial freighters.</string>
    <string name="antonov74">The Antonov An-74 (NATO reporting name: Coaler) is a Soviet/Ukrainian transport aircraft, developed by Antonov. It is a variant of the An-72.The An-72 and An-74 get their nickname, Cheburashka, from the large engine intake ducts, which resemble the oversized ears of the popular Soviet animated character of the same name.</string>
    <string name="antonov8">In December 1951, OKB-153 initiated the design of a twin-engine assault transport aircraft, designated DT-5/8 (Desahntno-Trahnsportnyy [samolyot] – assault transport aircraft), to be powered by two Kuznetsov TV-2 turboprop engines, and fitted with a large rear cargo door to allow vehicles to be driven straight into the hold.</string>

    //Bell
    <string name="bell204">The Bell 204 and 205 are the civilian versions of the UH-1 Iroquois single-engine military helicopter of the Huey family of helicopters.  They are type-certificated in the transport category and are used in a wide variety of applications, including crop dusting, cargo lifting and aerial firefighting.</string>
    <string name="bell206">The Bell 206 is a family of two-bladed, single- and twin-engine helicopters, manufactured by Bell Helicopter at its Mirabel, Quebec plant. Originally developed as the Bell YOH-4 for the United States Army\'s Light Observation Helicopter program, it was not selected by the Army.  Bell redesigned the airframe and successfully marketed the aircraft commercially as the five-place Bell 206A JetRanger. The new design was eventually selected by the Army as the OH-58 Kiowa.</string>
    <string name="bell207">The Bell 207 Sioux Scout was a modified Bell 47 helicopter, developed by Bell Helicopter under contract from the United States Army, as a proof-of-concept demonstrator for the Bell D-255 helicopter gunship design, featuring a tandem cockpit, stub wings, and a chin-mounted gun turret.</string>
    <string name="bell212">The Bell 212 (also known as the Twin Two-Twelve) is a two-blade, twin-engine, medium helicopter that first flew in 1968.  Originally manufactured by Bell Helicopter in Fort Worth, Texas, United States, production was moved to Mirabel, Quebec, Canada in 1988, along with all Bell commercial helicopter production after that plant opened in 1986.  The 212 is marketed to civilian operators and has a fifteen-seat configuration, with one pilot and fourteen passengers.  In cargo configuration the 212 has an internal capacity of 220 ft³ (6.23 m³). An external load of up to 5,000 lb (2,268 kg) can be carried.</string>
    <string name="bell214">The Bell 214 is a medium-lift helicopter derived from Bell Helicopter\'s ubiquitous UH-1 Huey series. The Bell 214ST shares the same model number, but is a larger, much-modified twin-engine derivative.</string>
    <string name="bell214ST">The Bell 214ST is a medium-lift, twin-engine helicopter descended from Bell Helicopter\'s ubiquitous UH-1 Huey series. Though it shares a type number with the somewhat-related Bell 214, the 214ST is larger and of quite different appearance.</string>
    <string name="bell222">The Bell 222 is an American twin-engine light helicopter built by Bell Helicopter. The Bell 230 is an improved development with different engines and other minor changes. A cosmetically modified version of the 222 was used as the titular aircraft in the American television series Airwolf.</string>
    <string name="bell407">The Bell 407 is a four-blade, single-engine, civil utility helicopter; a derivative of the Bell 206L-4 LongRanger. The 407 uses the four-blade, soft-in-plane design rotor with composite hub developed for the United States Army\'s OH-58D Kiowa Warrior instead of the two-blade, semi-rigid, teetering rotor of the 206L-4.</string>
    <string name="bell412">The Bell 412 is a twin-engine utility helicopter of the Huey family manufactured by Helicopter. It is a development of the Bell 212, with the major difference being the composite four-blade main rotor.</string>
    <string name="bell427">The Bell 427 is a twin-engine, multirole, light utility helicopter designed and manufactured by Bell Helicopter and Samsung Aerospace Industries. Its design is based on the Bell 407. It has been replaced in production by the lengthened Bell 429.</string>
    <string name="bell429">The Bell 429 GlobalRanger is a light, twin-engine helicopter developed by Bell Helicopter and Korea Aerospace Industries, based on the Bell 427.  First flight of the Bell 429 prototype took place on February 27, 2007, and the aircraft received type certification on July 1, 2009. The Bell 429 is capable of single-pilot IFR and Runway Category A operations.</string>
    <string name="bell403">The Bell 430 is an American twin-engine light-medium helicopter built by Bell Helicopter. It is a stretched and more powerful development of the Bell 230, which, in turn, was based on the earlier Bell 222.</string>
    <string name="bell47">The Bell 47 is a single rotor single engine light helicopter manufactured by Helicopter.  It was based on the third Bell 30 prototype, which was the company\'s first helicopter designed by Arthur M. Young.  The 47 became the first helicopter certified for civilian use on 8 March 1946. More than 5,600 Bell 47s were produced, including those under license by Agusta in Italy, Kawasaki Heavy Industries in Japan, and Westland Aircraft in the United Kingdom.  The Bell 47J Ranger is a modified version with a fully enclosed cabin and fuselage.</string>
    <string name="bell47J">The Bell 47J Ranger is an American single-engine single-rotor light helicopter manufactured by Bell Helicopter. It was an executive variant of the highly successful Bell 47 and was the first helicopter to carry a United States president.</string>
    <string name="bell525">The Bell 525 Relentless is an American medium-lift helicopter, under development by Bell Helicopter.  The Bell 525 was unveiled at the 2012 Heli-Expoin Dallas, Texas in February 2012. The helicopter first flew on 1 July 2015. It is designed to transport up to 19 passengers.</string>
    <string name="bellAH1Cobra">The Bell AH-1 Cobra is a two-blade, single-engine attack helicopter manufactured by Bell Helicopter.  It was developed using the engine, transmission and rotor system of the Bell UH-1 Iroquois. A member of the prolific Huey family, the AH-1 is also referred to as the HueyCobra or Snake.  The AH-1 was the backbone of the United States Army\'s attack helicopter fleet, but has been replaced by the AH-64 Apache in Army service.  Upgraded versions continue to fly with the militaries of several other nations.  The AH-1 twin-engine versions remain in service with United States Marine Corps(USMC) as the service\'s primary attack helicopter. Surplus AH-1 helicopters have been converted for fighting forest fires.</string>
    <string name="bellAH1supercobra">The Bell AH-1 SuperCobra is a twin-engine attack helicopter based on the United States Army\'s single-engine AH-1 Cobra. The twin Cobra family, itself part of the larger Huey family, includes the AH-1J SeaCobra, the AH-1T Improved SeaCobra, and the AH-1W SuperCobra.  The AH-1W, the backbone of the United States Marine Corps\'s attack helicopter fleet for decades, is being replaced by the next generation Bell AH-1Z Viper.</string>
    <string name="bellH12">The Bell R-12 (later predesignated H-12) (company Model 48) was an American 1940s military utility helicopter built by the Bell Helicopter company.</string>
    <string name="bellH13">The Bell H-13 Sioux was a single-engine single-rotor light helicopter built by Bell Helicopter. Westland Aircraft manufactured the Sioux under license for the British military as the Sioux AH.1 and HT.2.</string>
    <string name="bellHSL">The Bell HSL (Model 61) was an American 1950s anti-submarine warfare (ASW) helicopter built by the Bell Helicopter company, the only rotor type designed by Bell.</string>
    <string name="bellUH1">The Bell UH-1 Iroquois (nicknamed Huey) is a utility military helicopter powered by a single turboshaft engine, with two-blade main and tail rotors.  The first member of the prolific Huey family, it was developed by Bell Helicopter to meet a United States Army\'s 1952 requirement for a evacuation and utility helicopter, and first flew in 1956.  The UH-1 was the first turbine-powered helicopter to enter production in 1960 for the United States military, and more than 16,000 have been built since.  The Iroquois was originally designated HU-1, hence the Huey nickname, which has remained in common use, despite the official redesignation to UH-1 in 1962. The UH-1 first saw service in combat operations during the Vietnam War, with around 7,000 helicopters deployed.  The Bell 204 and 205 are Iroquois versions developed for the civil market.</string>
    <string name="BellXH15">The Bell XH-15 (Bell Model 54) was an American four-seat utility helicopter designed and built by Bell Helicopter, to meet a requirement for a liaison and utility helicopter for the United States Army and United States Air Force.</string>


    //Boeing
    <string name="boeing707">The Boeing 707 is a mid-sized, long-range, narrow-body, four-engine jet airliner built by Boeing Commercial Airplanes from 1958 to 1979. Its name is commonly pronounced as seven oh seven. Versions of the aircraft have a capacity from 140 to 219 passengers and a range of 2,500 to 5,750 nautical miles (2,880 to 6,620 mi; 4,630 to 10,650 km).</string>
    <string name="boeing717_200">The Boeing 717 is a twin-engine, single-aisle jet airliner, developed for the 100-seat market. The airliner was designed and originally marketed by McDonnell Douglas as the MD-95, a derivative of the DC-9 family. Capable of seating up to 134 passengers, the 717 has a design range of 2,060 nautical miles (3,815 km). It is powered by two Rolls-Royce BR715 turbofan engines mounted at the rear of the fuselage.</string>
    <string name="boeing720">The Boeing 720 is a four-engine narrow-body short- to medium-range passenger jet airliner. Developed by Boeing in the late 1950s from the Boeing 707, the 720 has a shorter fuselage and a shorter range. The 720 first flew in November 1959 and the model entered service with launch customer United Airlines in July 1960.</string>
    <string name="boeing727">The Boeing 727 is a midsized, narrow-body three-engine jet aircraft built by Boeing Commercial Airplanes from the early 1960s to 1984. It can carry 149 to 189 passengers and later models can fly up to 2,700 nautical miles (5,000 km) nonstop. Intended for short and medium-length flights, the 727 can use relatively short runways at smaller airports. It has three Pratt and Whitney JT8D engines below the T-tail, one on each side of the rear fuselage with a center engine that connects through an S-duct to an inlet at the base of the fin. The 727 is Boeing\'s only tree jet aircraft.</string>
    <string name="boeing737_classic">The Boeing 737 Classic refers to the 300/400/500 series of the Boeing 737. It is the second-generation derivative of the 737, following the original 100/200 models that began production in 1966.  They are short- to medium-range, narrow-body jet airliners. Produced by Boeing Commercial Airplanes from 1984 to 2000, the 737 Classic includes three variants and can seat between 145 and 188 passengers.  Improvements over the previous generation of 737 aircraft included CFM International CFM56 high-bypass-ratio turbofan engines, upgraded avionics, and increased passenger capacity (in the 300/400 models).</string>
    <string name="boeing737_max">The Boeing 737 MAX is an American narrow-body aircraft series designed and produced by Boeing Commercial Airplanes as the fourth generation of the Boeing 737, succeeding the Boeing 737 Next Generation (NG).</string>
    <string name="boeing737_ng">The Boeing 737 Next Generation, commonly abbreviated as 737NG is the name given to the 600/-700/800/900 series of the Boeing 737 airliner. It is the third generation derivative of the 737, and follows the 737 Classic (300/400/500) series, which began production in the 1980s. They are short to medium-range, narrow-body jet airliners powered by two engines. Produced since 1996 by Boeing Commercial Airplanes, the 737NG series includes four variants and can seat between 110 and 210 passengers.</string>
    <string name="boeing737_original">The Boeing 737 is a short- to  medium-range twin-jet narrow-body airliner developed and manufactured by Boeing Commercial Airplanes in the United States. Originally developed as a shorter, lower-cost twin-engine airliner derived from the 707 and 727, the 737 has developed into a family of ten passenger models with capacities from 85 to 215 passengers. It was immediately realized that most airlines wanted a slightly higher passenger load, to which Boeing responded with the 737-200. Two sections were added to the fuselage.</string>
    <string name="boeing747">The Boeing 747 is an American wide-body commercial jet airliner and cargo aircraft, often referred to by its original nickname, Jumbo Jet. Its distinctive hump upper deck along the forward part of the aircraft has made it one of the most recognizable aircraft, and it was the first wide-body airplane produced. Manufactured by Boeing\'s Commercial Airplane unit in the United States, the 747 was originally envisioned to have 150 percent greater capacity than the Boeing 707, a common large commercial aircraft of the 1960s</string>
    <string name="boeing747_8">The Boeing 747-8 is a wide-body jet airliner developed by Boeing Commercial Airplanes. It was officially announced in 2005. The 747-8 is the third generation of the 747, with a lengthened fuselage, redesigned wings, new engines, and improved efficiency. The 747-8 is the largest 747 version, the largest commercial aircraft built in the United States, and the longest passenger aircraft in the world.</string>
    <string name="boeing757">The Boeing 757 is a mid-size, narrow-body twin-engine jet airliner that was designed and built by Boeing Commercial Airplanes. It is the manufacturer\'s largest single-aisle passenger aircraft and was produced from 1981 to 2004. The twin-jet has a two-crew member glass cockpit, turbofan engines of sufficient power to allow takeoffs from relatively short runways and higher altitudes, a conventional tail and, for reduced aerodynamic drag, a super critical wing design.</string>
    <string name="boeing767">The Boeing 767 is a mid-to large-size, mid- to long-range, wide-body twin-engine jet airliner built by Boeing Commercial Airplanes.  It was Boeing\'s first wide-body twin-jet and its first airliner with a two-crew glass cockpit. The aircraft has two turbofan engines, a conventional tail, and, for reduced aerodynamic drag, a supercritical wing design. Designed as a smaller wide-body airliner than earlier aircraft such as the 747, the 767 has a seating capacity for 181 to 375 people, and a design range of 3,850 to 6,385 nautical miles (7,130 to 11,825 km), depending on variant.</string>
    <string name="boeing777">The Boeing 777 is a long-range wide-body twin-engine jet airliner developed and manufactured by Boeing Commercial Airplanes. It is the world\'s largest twinjet and has a typical seating capacity of 314 to 396 passengers, with a range of 5,240 to 8,555 nautical miles (9,704 to 15,844 km).</string>
    <string name="boeing777_x">The Boeing 777X is a new series of the long-range wide-body twin-engine Boeing 777 family that is under development by Boeing Commercial Airplanes.  The 777X is to feature GE9X new engines, new composite wings with folding wingtips, a denser cabin, and technologies from the Boeing 787.  The 777X series was launched in November 2013 with two variants: the 777-8 and the 777-9.</string>
    <string name="boeing787">Boeing 787 Dreamliner is an American long-haul, mid-size wide body, twin-engine jet airliner made by Boeing Commercial Airplanes. Its variants seat 242 to 335 passengers in typical three-class seating configurations.  It is the first airliner with an airframe constructed primarily of composite materials. The 787 was designed to be 20% more fuel-efficient than the Boeing 767, which it was intended to replace.</string>

    // C
    <string name="c12">The Beechcraft C-12 Huron is the military designation for a series of twin-engine turboprop aircraft based on the Beechcraft Super King Air and Beechcraft 1900.  C-12 variants are used by the United States Air Force, United States Army, United States Navy and United States Marine Corps.  These aircraft are used for various duties, including embassy support, medical evacuation, as well as passenger and light cargo transport. Some aircraft are modified with surveillance systems for various missions, including the Cefly Lancer, RC-12 Guardrail and Project Liberty programs.</string>
    <string name="c130">The Lockheed C-130 Hercules is a four-engine turboprop military transport aircraft designed and built originally by Lockheed (now Lockheed Martin). Capable of using unprepared runways for takeoffs and landings, the C-130 was originally designed as a troop, medevac, and cargo transport aircraft.  The versatile airframe has found uses in a variety of other roles, including as a gunship (AC-130), for airborne assault, search and rescue, scientific research support, weather reconnaissance, aerial refueling, maritime patrol, and aerial firefighting.  It is now the main tactical airlifter for many military forces worldwide. More than 40 variants of the Hercules, including a civilian one marketed as the Lockheed L-100, operate in more than 60 nations.</string>
    <string name="c130j">The Lockheed Martin C-130J Super Hercules is a four-engine turboprop military transport aircraft. The C-130J is a comprehensive update of the Lockheed C-130 Hercules, with new engines, flight deck, and other systems.  The Hercules family has the longest continuous production run of any military aircraft in history. During more than 60 years of service, the family has participated in military, civilian, and humanitarian aid operations.  The Hercules has outlived several planned successor designs, most notably the Advanced Medium STOL Transport contestants. Fifteen nations have placed orders for a total of 300 C-130Js, of which 250 aircraft have been delivered as of February 2012.</string>
    <string name="c144">The EADS HC-144 Ocean Sentry is a medium-range, twin-engine aircraft used by the United States Coast Guard in the search-and-rescue and maritime patrol missions.  Based on the Airbus Military CN-235 it was procured as a Medium Range Surveillance Aircraft.  The HC-144 is supplied by Airbus Group, Inc. formerly EADS North America and is built in Spain by Airbus Military.</string>
    <string name="c146">The Dornier 328 is a turboprop-powered commuter airliner. Initially produced by Dornier Luftfahrt GmbH, the firm was acquired in 1996 by Fairchild Aircraft. The resulting firm, named Fairchild-Dornier, manufactured the 328 family in Oberpfaffenhofen, Germany, conducted sales from San Antonio, Texas, United States, and supported the product line from both locations.  There is also a jet-powered version of the aircraft, the Fairchild Dornier 328JET.</string>
    <string name="c17">The Boeing C-17 Globemaster III is a large military transport aircraft. It was developed for the United States Air Force (USAF) from the 1980s to the early 1990s by McDonnell Douglas.  The C-17 carries forward the name of two previous piston-engine military cargo aircraft, the Douglas C-74 Globemaster and the Douglas C-124 Globemaster II. The C-17 commonly performs tactical and strategic airlift missions, transporting troops and cargo throughout the world; additional roles include medical evacuation and airdrop duties. It was designed to replace the Lockheed C-141 Starlifter, and also fulfill some of the duties of the Lockheed C-5 Galaxy, freeing the C-5 fleet for outsize cargo.</string>
    <string name="c26">The Fairchild C-26 Metroliner is the designation for the Fairchild Swearingen Metroliner series twin turboprop aircraft in the service of the United States military. It was not officially named by the US Armed Forces, but is unofficially known by the same name as its civilian counterpart.  The C-26A is the military version of the Model SA227-AC Metro III; the C-26B is the military version of the Model SA227-BC Metro III and Model SA227-DC Metro 23; and UC-26C is the military designation for the Model SA227-AT Merlin IVC.</string>
    <string name="c5">The Lockheed C-5 Galaxy is a large military transport aircraft originally designed and built by Lockheed, and now maintained and upgraded by its successor, Lockheed Martin.  It provides the United States Air Force (USAF) with a heavy intercontinental-range strategic airlift capability, one that can carry outsize and oversize loads, including all air-certifiable cargo.  The Galaxy has many similarities to its smaller Lockheed C-141 Starlifter predecessor, and the later Boeing C-17 Globemaster III. The C-5 is among the largest military aircraft in the world.</string>

    //Eurocopter
    <string name="eurocopterAS532">The Eurocopter AS532 Cougar (now Airbus Helicopters H215M) is a twin-engine, medium-weight, multipurpose helicopter developed by France. The AS532 is a development and upgrade of the Aerospatiale SA 330 Puma in its militarized form.  *Its civilian counterpart is the Eurocopter AS332 Super Puma*  The AS532 has been further developed as the Eurocopter EC725.</string>
    <string name="eurocopterAS565">The Eurocopter (now Airbus Helicopters) AS565 Panther is the military version of the Eurocopter AS365 Dauphin medium-weight multi-purpose twin-engine helicopter.  The Panther is used for a wide range of military roles, including combat assault, fire support, anti-submarine warfare, anti-surface warfare, search and rescue, and medical evacuation (MEDEVAC)</string>
    <string name="eurocopterEC635">The Eurocopter EC635 (now Airbus Helicopters H135M) is a multi-purpose light helicopter developed by Eurocopter as a military version of the Eurocopter EC135.  It is a twin-engine aircraft and can carry up to 8 people, including the pilot, and a range of military equipment or armaments.  The helicopter is marketed for troop transport, medical evacuation, cargo transport, reconnaissance and surveillance and armed combat support missions.</string>
    <string name="eurocopterEC725">The Eurocopter EC725 Caracal *now called Airbus Helicopters H225M* is a long-range tactical transport military helicopter developed from the Eurocopter AS532 Cougar for military use. It is a twin-engine aircraft and can carry up to 29 seated troops along with two crew, depending on customer configuration.  The helicopter is marketed for troop transport, casualty evacuation, and combat search and rescue duties, and is similar to the civilian EC225.</string>
    <string name="eurocopterFennec">The Eurocopter (now Airbus Helicopters) AS550 Fennec (now H125M) and AS555 Fennec 2 are lightweight, multipurpose helicopters manufactured by Eurocopter Group. Based on the AS350 Ecureuil and AS355 Ecureuil 2 series, they are named after the fennec fox. The armed versions of the AS550 and AS555 can be fitted with coaxial weapons, rockets, torpedoes and various other munitions.</string>
    <string name="eurocopterHH65">The Eurocopter HH-65 Dolphin is a twin-engine, single main rotor, medevac-capable search and rescue (SAR) helicopter operated by the United States Coast Guard (USCG). It is a variant of the French-built Eurocopter AS365 Dauphin.</string>
    <string name="eurocopterTiger">The Eurocopter (now Airbus Helicopters) Tiger is a four-bladed, twin-engine attack helicopter which first entered service in 2003. It is manufactured by Eurocopter (now Airbus Helicopters), the successor company to Aerospatiale’s and DASA\'s respective helicopter divisions, which designate it as the EC665.  Following their languages, in Germany it is known as the Tiger; in France and Spain it is called the Tiger.  Development of the Tiger started during the Cold War, and it was initially intended as an anti-tank helicopter platform to be used against a Soviet ground invasion of Western Europe.</string>
    <string name="eurocopterUH72">The Eurocopter (now Airbus Helicopters) UH-72 Lakota is a twin-engine helicopter with a single four-bladed main rotor. The UH-72 is a militarized version of the Eurocopter EC145 and was built by American Eurocopter, a division of Airbus Group, Inc. Initially marketed as the UH-145, the helicopter was selected as the winner of the United States Army\'s Light Utility Helicopter (LUH) program on 30 June 2006.</string>

    //F
    <string name="f14">The Grumman F-14 Tomcat is an American supersonic, twin-engine, two-seat, twin-tail, variable-sweep wing fighter aircraft. The Tomcat was developed for the United States Navy\'s Naval Fighter Experimental (VFX) program after the collapse of the F-111B project. The F-14 was the first of the American teen-series fighters, which were designed incorporating air combat experience against MiG fighters during the Vietnam War.</string>
    <string name="f15">The McDonnell Douglas F-15 Eagle is an American twin-engine, all-weather tactical fighter aircraft designed by McDonnell Douglas (now Boeing) to gain and maintain air supremacy in all aspects of aerial combat. Following reviews of proposals, the United States Air Force selected McDonnell Douglas design in 1967 to meet the service\'s need for a dedicated air superiority fighter. The Eagle first flew in July 1972, and entered service in 1976. It is among the most successful modern fighters, with over 100 victories and no losses in aerial combat, with the majority of the kills by the Israeli Air Force.</string>
    <string name="f16">The General Dynamics F-16 Fighting Falcon is a single-engine supersonic multirole fighter aircraft originally developed by General Dynamics (now Lockheed Martin) for the United States Air Force (USAF). Designed as an air superiority day fighter, it evolved into a successful all-weather multirole aircraft.</string>
    <string name="f18">The McDonnell Douglas F/A-18 Hornet is a twin-engine, supersonic, all-weather, carrier-capable, multirole combat jet, designed as both a fighter and attack aircraft (hence the F/A designation).  Designed by McDonnell Douglas (now Boeing) and Northrop, the F/A-18 was derived from the latter\'s YF-17 in the 1970s for use by the United States Navy and Marine Corps.</string>
    <string name="f35">The Lockheed Martin F-35 Lightning II is a family of single-seat, single-engine, all-weather stealth multirole fighters. The fifth-generation combat aircraft is designed to perform ground attack and air superiority missions.</string>
    <string name="f22">The Lockheed Martin F-22 Raptor is a fifth-generation, single-seat, twin-engine, all-weather stealth tactical fighter aircraft developed for the United States Air Force (USAF).  The result of the USAF\'s Advanced Tactical Fighter program, the aircraft was designed primarily as an air superiority fighter, but also has ground attack, electronic warfare, and signal intelligence capabilities.</string>
    <string name="f4">The McDonnell Douglas F-4 Phantom II is a tandem two-seat, twin-engine, all-weather, long-range supersonic jet interceptor and fighter-bomberoriginally developed for the United States Navy by Aircraft. It first entered service in 1960 with the U.S. Navy. Proving highly adaptable, it was also adopted by the U.S. Marine Corps and the U.S. Air Force, and by the mid-1960s had become a major part of their air wings.</string>
    <string name="f5">The Northrop F-5A and F-5B Freedom Fighter and the F-5E and F-5F Tiger II are part of a supersonic light fighter family, initially designed in the late 1950s by Northrop Corporation. Being smaller and simpler than contemporaries such as the McDonnell Douglas F-4 Phantom II, the F-5 cost less to both procure and operate, making it a popular export aircraft.</string>

    //Fokker
    <string name="fokker100">The Fokker 100 is a medium-sized, twin-turbofan jet airliner from Fokker, the largest such aircraft built by the company before its bankruptcy in 1996. The type possessed low operational costs and initially had scant competition in the 100-seat short-range regional jet class, contributing to strong sales upon introduction in the late 1980s.</string>
    <string name="fokker25">The Fokker F.25 Promotor, first flown in 1946, was a single-engine, twin-boomed, four-passenger monoplane with a pusher engine mounted at the rear of a central nacelle. It was of wooden construction and has fitted with a retractable nose wheel undercarriage.</string>
    <string name="fokker27">The Fokker F27 Friendship is a turboprop airliner developed and manufactured by the Dutch aircraft manufacturer Fokker. It has the distinction of being the most numerous post-war aircraft to have been manufactured in the Netherlands; the F27 was also one of the most successful European airliners of its era.</string>
    <string name="fokker28">The Fokker F28 Fellowship is a short range jet airliner designed and built by Dutch aircraft manufacturer Fokker.</string>
    <string name="fokker50">The Fokker 50 is a turbo prop-powered airliner, designed as a refinement of and successor to the highly successful Fokker F27 Friendship. The Fokker 60 is a stretched freighter version of the Fokker 50. Both aircraft were manufactured and supported by Dutch aircraft manufacturer Fokker.</string>
    <string name="fokker70">The Fokker 70 is a narrow-body, twin-engine, medium-range, turbofan regional airliner produced by Fokker as a smaller version of the Fokker 100.  Both the F70 and F100 were preceded by the first jet airliner manufactured by Fokker, the Fokker F28 Fellowship.  Since its first flight in 1993, 47 aircraft, plus one prototype, have been manufactured and 23 are still in active service with airlines around the world.</string>
    <string name="fokkerS13">The Fokker S.13 Universal Trainer is a dual engine propeller aircraft for training purposes designed and manufactured by the former Dutch aircraft manufacturer Fokker.</string>
    <string name="fokkerS14">The Fokker S-14 Mach trainer was a Dutch two-seater military training jet aircraft designed and manufactured by Fokker for the Royal Netherlands Air Force. Development started in the late 1940s, and it was one of the first jet fighter training aircraft in the world, making its first flight on 19 May 1951 and entering service in 1955.</string>

    //Ilyushin
    <string name="Ilyushin10">The Ilyushin Il-10 -Cyrillic Илью́шин Ил-10- -NATO reporting name: ‘Beast’- was a Soviet ground attack aircraft developed at the end of World War II by the Ilyushin construction bureau. It was also license-built in Czechoslovakia by Avia as the Avia B-33.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin102">The Ilyushin Il-102 was an experimental jet-powered ground-attack aircraft designed by Ilyushin. This aircraft was never chosen for production, being surpassed by the Su-25, and only a few development prototypes were built.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin103">The Ilyushin Il-103 is a single-engine, low-wing training aircraft developed by the Ilyushin Design Bureau starting in 1990 in the Soviet Union. The aircraft is now produced in Russia. It was the first Russian aircraft to achieve Federal Aviation Administration certification, in 1998, for sales in the United States.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin112">The Ilyushin Il-112 is a high-wing light military transport aircraft being developed by Ilyushin Aviation Complex (JSC IL) for air landing and airdrop of military air cargoes, equipment and personnel. The aircraft is being manufactured by Voronezh Aircraft Production Association.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin114">The Ilyushin Il-114 (Russian Илью́шин Ил-114) is a Russian twin-engine turboprop airliner, designed for local routes. Intended to replace Antonov An-24, it first flew in 1990. A total of 20 Il-114s have been built. Production of the Il-114 was temporarily suspended in July 2012, with the sixth and last aircraft delivered to Uzbekistan Airlines on 24 May 2013. In 2016, the company stated that production would be restarted with all-Russian parts, with a new first flight in 2019 and the first aircraft in commercial service in 2021.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin12">The Ilyushin Il-12 (NATO reporting name: Coach) was a Soviet twin-engine cargo aircraft, developed in the mid-1940s for small and medium-haul airline routes and as a military transport.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin14">The Ilyushin Il-14 (NATO reporting name: Crate) was a Soviet twin-engine commercial and military personnel and cargo transport aircraft that first flew in 1950, and entered service in 1954. Il-14 was also manufactured in East Germany by VVB Flugzeugbau, in Czechoslovakia as the Avia 14. The Ilyushin Il-14 was typically replaced by the Antonov An-24 and Yakovlev Yak-40.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin16">The Ilyushin Il-16 (Cyrillic Илью́шин Ил-16) was a Soviet lightweight armored ground-attack aircraft developed at the end of World War II by the Ilyushin design bureau. It was in essence a scaled-down version of the Ilyushin Il-10, but was fitted with a newly developed Mikulin AM-43NV engine with the expectation that it would be faster and more maneuverable than its predecessor.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin18">The Ilyushin Il-18 -Russian: Илью́шин Ил-18- -NATO reporting name: Coot- is a large turboprop airliner that first flew in 1957 and became one of the best known and durable Soviet aircraft of its era. The Il-18 was one of the world\'s principal airliners for several decades and was widely exported.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin18_1946">The Ilyushin Il-18 was a Soviet four-engine airliner designed and built by Ilyushin immediately after World War II. Although the aircraft itself was successful, its Shvetsov ASh-73TK engines were too unreliable for civilian use and were further needed to equip the Tupolev Tu-4 bomber, so it was cancelled in 1948.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin2">The Ilyushin Il-2 (Cyrillic: Илью́шин Ил-2) Shturmovik (Cyrillic: Штурмови́к, Shturmovík) was a aircraft produced by the Soviet Union in large numbers during the Second World War.  With 36,183 units of the Il-2 produced during the war, and in combination with its successor, the Ilyushin Il-10, a total of 42,330 were built, making it the single most produced military aircraft design in aviation history, as well as one of the most produced piloted aircraft in history along with the American postwar civilian Cessna 172 and the Soviet Union\'s own then-contemporary Polikarpov Po-2 Kukuruznik multipurpose biplane.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin22">The Ilyushin Il-22- USAF/DOD- designation Type 10, was the first Soviet jet-engine bomber to fly. It used four Lyulka TR-1turbojets carried on short horizontal pylons ahead and below the wing. The engines did not meet their designed thrust ratings and their fuel consumption was higher than planned. These problems meant that the aircraft could not reach its required performance and it was cancelled on 22 September 1947.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin28">The Ilyushin Il-28 -Russian: Илью́шин Ил-28 -NATO reporting name: Beagle- is a jet bomber of the immediate postwar period that was originally manufactured for the Soviet Air Forces. It was the Soviet Union\'s first such aircraft to enter large-scale production. It was also licence-built in China as the Harbin H-5.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin30">The Ilyushin Il-30 was a Soviet turbojet-powered tactical bomber designed as a higher-performance, swept wing version of the Ilyushin Il-28, in the late 1940s. Its thin wing and engine nacelles necessitated the use of tandem landing gear, the first Soviet aircraft to do so. It was apparently canceled before the prototype made its first flight, although sources disagree with this.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin32">The Ilyushin Il-32 was a Soviet heavy military glider developed after World War II to deliver 7,000 kg (15,000 lb) of cargo. To facilitate loading and unloading, the glider\'s nose and tail sections were hinged to swing sideways.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin40">The Ilyushin Il-40 (NATO reporting name: Brawny) was a two-seat Soviet jet-engined armored ground-attack aircraft. The first prototype flew in 1953 and was very successful except when it fired its guns, as their combustion gasses disturbed the airflow into the engines and caused them to flameout or hiccup.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin54">The Il-54 was a transonic bomber developed in the USSR in the 1950s. Only two examples were built before the project was abandoned. The Council of Ministers issued a directive to OKB-115, for a transonic bomber prototype to be submitted for State Acceptance Trials in July 1954. The design of this bomber went through several stages before settling on the final configuration.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin6">The Ilyushin Il-6 was a Soviet long-range bomber developed from the Ilyushin Il-4 during 1942. Originally intended as a high-speed replacement for the Il-4, it was recast as a very long-range bomber with fuel-conserving diesel engines before production of the single prototype began in December 1942.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin62">The Ilyushin IL-62 -Russian: Илью́шин Ил-62- -NATO reporting name: Classic-is a Soviet long-range narrow-body jet airliner conceived in 1960 by Ilyushin. As successor to the popular turboprop Il-18 and with capacity for almost 200 passengers and crew, the Il-62 was the world\'s largest jet airliner when first flown in 1963.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin76">The Ilyushin Il-76 -Russian: Илью́шин Ил-76- -NATO reporting name: Candid- is a multi-purpose four-engine turbofan strategic airlifter designed by the Soviet Union\'s Ilyushin design bureau. It was first planned as a commercial freighter in 1967, as a replacement for the Antonov An-12. It was designed to deliver heavy machinery to remote, poorly served areas. Military versions of the Il-76 have been widely used in Europe, Asia and Africa, including use as an aerial refueling tanker or command center.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin78">The Ilyushin Il-78 -Russian: Илью́шин Ил-78- -NATO reporting name Midas- is a Soviet four-engined aerial refueling tanker based on the Il-76.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin80">The Ilyushin Il-80 (NATO reporting name: Maxdome) is a Russian airborne command and control aircraft. It is a modified Ilyushin Il-86 airliner</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin86">The Ilyushin Il-86- Russian: Илью́шин Ил-86- -NATO reporting name: Camber- is a short/medium-range wide-body jet airliner. It was the USSR\'s first wide-body and the world\'s second four-engine wide-body. Designed and tested by the Ilyushin design bureau in the 1970s, it was certified by the Soviet aircraft industry, manufactured and marketed by the USSR.</string>
    <string name="Ilyushin96">The Ilyushin Il-96 (Russian: Илью́шин Ил-96) is a Russian four-engine long-haul wide-body airliner designed by Ilyushin in the former Soviet Union and manufactured by the Voronezh Aircraft Production Association in Russia. It is powered by four Aviadvigatel PS-90 two-shaft turbofan engines.</string>
    <string name="IlyushinDB3">The Ilyushin DB-3, where DB stands for Dalniy Bombardirovschik (Russian: Дальний бомбардировщик) meaning long-range bomber, was a Soviet bomber of World War II. It was a twin-engine, low-wing monoplane that first flew in 1935.</string>

    //Kamov
    <string name="Kamov115">The Kamov Ka-115 Moskvichka is a light multi-purpose helicopter designed for many uses, including passenger and cargo transportation, emergency service, SAR and patrol, or charter flights.</string>
    <string name="Kamov18">The Kamov Ka-18 (NATO reporting name Hog) was a Soviet four-seat utility helicopter that first flew in 1955. It was a development of the Kamov Ka-15, with a lengthened fuselage and a more powerful engine - the 255 hp Ivchenko AI-14V radial. Total production from Kamov was about 120 units.</string>
    <string name="Kamov20">The Kamov Ka-20 (NATO reporting name Harp) was a Soviet twin-engine prototype helicopter designed and built by Kamov that led to the Ka-25family of helicopters.  Developed from the earlier Ka-15 to meet a 1958 Soviet Navy requirement for a heavy shipborne helicopter, the Ka-20 had the similar twin contra-rotating, three-blade rotors of the earlier Ka-15 design and was powered by two 670 kW turboshaft engines.  The Ka-20 first became known outside the Soviet Union at the 1961 Tushino Aviation Day display where a Ka-20 was demonstrated fitted with dummy missiles on the cabin sides.</string>
    <string name="Kamov226">The Kamov Ka-226 is a small, twin-engine Russian utility helicopter. The Ka-226 features an interchangeable mission pod, rather than a conventional cabin, allowing the use of various accommodation or equipment configurations. The Ka-226 entered service in 2002. Variants of the Ka-226 have the NATO reporting name of Hoodlum.</string>
    <string name="Kamov25">The Kamov Ka-25 (NATO reporting name Hormone) was a naval helicopter, developed for the Soviet Navy in the USSR from 1958.</string>
    <string name="Kamov26">The Kamov Ka-26 (NATO reporting name Hoodlum) is a Soviet light utility helicopter with co-axial rotors.</string>
    <string name="Kamov27">The Kamov Ka-27 (NATO reporting name \'Helix\') is a military helicopter developed for the Soviet Navy, and currently in service in various countries including Russia, Ukraine, Vietnam, China, South Korea, and India. Variants include the Ka-29 assault transport, the Ka-28 downgraded export version, and the Ka-32 for civilian use.</string>
    <string name="Kamov31">The Kamov Ka-31 (NATO reporting name \'Helix\') is a military helicopter developed for the Soviet Navy and currently in service in Russia, China and India in the naval airborne early warning and control role.  As with all Kamov helicopters except the Ka-60/-62 family, the Ka-31 has co-axially mounted contra-rotating main rotors.  The airframe of the Ka-31 is based on the Kamov Ka-27. One visually distinctive feature of the Ka-31 is the large antenna of the early-warning radar, which is either rotating or folded and stowed under the fuselage. The second is the reduction of the bulky electro-optical sensory suite beneath the cockpit. The landing gear retracts in order to prevent interference with the radar.</string>
    <string name="Kamov35">The Kamov Ka-35 (or Ka-31SV/Ka-252SV) is the newest Russian early warning radar-carrying rotary-wing aircraft. The Ka-35 has passed all tests and has been authorized for service. It is equipped with a rotating laterally oriented antenna of the L381 complex. In late October 2016, the helicopter was deployed to Syria.</string>
    <string name="Kamov37">The Kamov Ka-37 is an unmanned helicopter designed for aerial photography, television and radio broadcasting, delivery of medicines, food, mail, and emergency aid in disasters or hard and dangerous environments, and later several military roles.  The aircraft uses coaxial rotors and a 45 kW engine. The operator may be located in a vehicle with monitors and flight controls, or with a simple hand-held radio controller.</string>
    <string name="Kamov40">The Kamov Ka-40 is reported to be  a new anti-submarine helicopter based on the Ka-27 and has been under development since 1990. The design was based on and fit to replace the Ka-27 with a pointed streamlined nose. Although the Ka-40 was proposed for several civil and military roles, development was suspended in 1998.</string>
    <string name="Kamov50">The Kamov Ka-50 Black Shark (Russian:Chornaya Akula) (NATO reporting name: Hokum A) is a single-seat Russian attack helicopter with the distinctive coaxial rotor system of the Kamov design bureau. It was designed in the 1980s and adopted for service in the Russian army in 1995. It is manufactured by the Progress company in Arsenyev. It is used as a heavily armed helicopter. It is the world\'s first operational helicopter with a rescue ejection system.</string>
    <string name="Kamov60">The Kamov Ka-60/62 Kasatka (Russian: Касатка: Killer whale) is a Russian helicopter that first flew on 24 December 1998.</string>

    //Mig
    <string name="Mig21">The Mikoyan-Gurevich MiG-21 -Russian: Микоян и Гуревич МиГ 21- -NATO reporting name: Fishbed- is a supersonic jet fighter and interceptor aircraft, designed by the Mikoyan-Gurevich Design Bureau in the Soviet Union.</string>
    <string name="Mig23">The Mikoyan-Gurevich MiG-23 -Russian: Микоян и Гуревич МиГ 23- -NATO reporting name: Flogger- is a variable-geometry fighter aircraft, designed by the Mikoyan-Gurevich design bureau in the Soviet Union. It is considered to belong to the Soviet third-generation jet fighter category, along with similarly aged Soviet fighters such as the MiG-25 Foxbat.</string>
    <string name="Mig25">The Mikoyan-Gurevich MiG-25 -Russian: Микоян и Гуревич МиГ 25- -NATO reporting name: Foxbat- is a supersonic interceptor and reconnaissance aircraft that was among the fastest military aircraft to enter service. It was designed by the Soviet Union\'s Mikoyan-Gurevich bureau, and is one of the few combat aircraft built primarily using stainless steel. It was the last plane designed by Mikhail Gurevich before his retirement.</string>
    <string name="Mig29">The Mikoyan MiG-29 -Russian: Микоян МиГ 29- -NATO reporting name: Fulcrum- is a twin-engine jet fighter aircraft designed in the Soviet Union.  Developed by the Mikoyan design bureau as an air superiority fighter during the 1970s, the MiG-29, along with the larger Sukhoi Su-27, was developed to counter new U.S. fighters such as the McDonnell Douglas F-15 Eagle and the General Dynamics F-16 Fighting Falcon.  The MiG-29 entered service with the Soviet Air Force in 1982.</string>
    <string name="Mig31">The Mikoyan MiG-31 -Russian: Микоян МиГ 31- -NATO reporting name: Foxhound- is a supersonic interceptor aircraft developed for use by the Soviet Air Forces. The aircraft was designed by the Mikoyan design bureau as a replacement for the earlier MiG-25 Foxbat; the MiG-31 is based on, and shares design elements with the MiG-25.</string>

    //Mill
    <string name="Mil1">The Mil Mi-1 (USAF/DoD reporting name Type 32 NATO reporting name Hare) was a Soviet three- or four-seat light utility helicopter. It was the first Soviet helicopter to enter serial production. It is powered by one 575 hp Ivchenko AI-26V radial. It entered service in 1950 and was first seen on the 1951 Soviet Aviation Day, Tushino and was produced for 16 years. More than 1,000 were built in the USSR and 1,594 in Poland, as SM-1.</string>
    <string name="Mil10">The Mil Mi-10 (NATO reporting name Harke) given the product number izdeliye 60 is a Soviet military transport helicopter of flying crane configuration, developed from the Mi-6, entering service in 1963.</string>
    <string name="Mil14">The Mil Mi-14 (Russian: Миль Ми-14) (NATO reporting name: Haze) is a Soviet shore-based nuclear-capable amphibious anti-submarine helicopter derived from the earlier Mi-8.</string>
    <string name="Mil17">The Mil Mi-17 (NATO reporting name: Hip) is a Russian helicopter in production at two factories in Kazan and Ulan-Ude. It is known as the Mi-8M series in Russian service. It is a medium twin-turbine transport helicopter. There are also armed gunship versions.</string>
    <string name="Mil2">The Mil Mi-2 (NATO reporting name Hoplite) is a small, lightly armored  urbine-powered transport helicopter that could also provide close air support when armed with 57 mm rockets and a 23 mm cannon.</string>
    <string name="Mil24">The Mil Mi-24 (Russian: Миль Ми-24) (NATO reporting name: Hind) is a large helicopter gunship, attack helicopter and low-capacity troop transport with room for eight passengers.  It is produced by Mil Moscow Helicopter Plant and has been operated since 1972 by the Soviet Air Force and its successors, along with more than 30 other nations.</string>
    <string name="Mil26">The Mil Mi-26 (Russian: Миль Ми-26) ( NATO reporting name: Halo) is a Soviet/Russian heavy transport helicopter. Its product code is izdeliye 90. Operated by both military and civilian operators, it is the largest and most powerful helicopter to have gone into series production.</string>
    <string name="Mil28">The Mil Mi-28 (NATO reporting name Havoc) is a Russian all-weather, day-night, military tandem, two-seat anti-armor attack helicopter. It is an attack helicopter with no intended secondary transport capability, better optimized than the Mil Mi-24 gunship for the role. It carries a single gun in an under nose barbette, plus external loads carried on pylons beneath stub wings.</string>
    <string name="Mil4">The Mil Mi-4 (USAF/DoD reporting name Type 36) ( NATO reporting name: Hound) is a Soviet transport helicopter that served in both military and civilian roles.</string>
    <string name="Mil6">The Mil Mi-6 (NATO reporting name Hook) given the article number izdeliye 50 and company designation V-6, was a Soviet/Russian heavy transport helicopter that was designed by the Mil design bureau. It was built in large numbers for both military and civil roles.</string>
    <string name="Mil8">The Mil Mi-8 (Russian: Ми-8) (NATO reporting name: Hip) is a medium twin-turbine helicopter, originally designed by the Soviet Union, and now produced by Russia.  In addition to its most common role as a transport helicopter, the Mi-8 is also used as an airborne command post, armed gunship, and reconnaissance platform.  Along with the related, more powerful Mil Mi-17, the Mi-8 is among the world\'s most-produced helicopters, used by over 50 countries. As of 2015, it is the third most common operational military aircraft in the world.</string>

    //Sukhoi
    <string name="Su24">The Sukhoi Su-24 -NATO reporting name: Fencer- is a supersonic, all-weather attack aircraft developed in the Soviet Union.  The aircraft has a variable-sweep wing, twin-engines and a side-by-side seating arrangement for its two crew.  It was the first of the USSR\'s aircraft to carry an integrated digital system. It remains in service with the Russian Air Force, Ukrainian Air Force, Azerbaijan Air Force and various air forces to which it was exported.</string>
    <string name="Su25">The Sukhoi Su-25 Grach -Russian: Грач (rook) NATO reporting name: -Frog foot- is a single-seat, twin-engine jet aircraft developed in the Union by Sukhoi.  It was designed to provide close air support for the Soviet Ground Forces. The first prototype made its maiden flight on 22 February 1975. After testing, the aircraft went into series production in 1978 at Tbilisi in the Georgian Soviet Socialist Republic.</string>
    <string name="Su27">The Sukhoi Su-27 -Russian: Сухой Су-27- -NATO reporting name: Flanker is a twin-engine super maneuverable fighter aircraft designed by Sukhoi.  It was intended as a direct competitor for the large United States fourth-generation fighters such as the Grumman F-14 Tomcat and F-15 Eagle, with3,530-kilometre range, heavy aircraft ordnance, sophisticated avionics and high maneuverability.</string>
    <string name="Su34">The Sukhoi Su-34 -Russian: Сухой Су-34- -NATO reporting name: Fullback- is a Russian twin-engine, twin-seat, all-weather supersonic medium-range fighter-bomber/aircraft. It first flew in 1990 and entered service in 2014 with the Russian Air Force.</string>
    <string name="Su35">The Sukhoi Su-35 -Russian: Сухой Су 35- -NATO reporting name: Flanker E- is the designation for two improved derivatives of the Su-27 air-defense fighter. They are single-seat, twin-engine, super maneuverable aircraft, designed by the Sukhoi Design Bureau and built by the Komsomolsk-on-Amur Aircraft Plant.</string>

    //Tupolev
    <string name="Tupolev1">The Tupolev Tu-1 was a prototype Soviet night fighter variant of the Tupolev Tu-2 medium bomber that first flew after the end of World War II. It was cancelled when its experimental Mikulin AM-43V engines reached the end of their service life.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev104">The Tupolev Tu-104 (NATO reporting name: Camel) was a twinjet medium-range narrow-body turbojet-powered Soviet airliner. It was the second to enter in regular service, behind the British *de Havilland Comet* and was the sole jetliner operating in the world from 1956 to 1958, when the British jetliner was grounded due to safety matters.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev110">The Tupolev Tu-110 (NATO reporting name: Cooker) was a jet airliner designed and built in the USSR, which saw its maiden flight in 1957.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev114">The Tupolev Tu-114 Rossiya (Russian: Tyполев Тy-114 Poccия) (NATO reporting name Cleat) was a turboprop-powered long-range airliner designed by the Tupolev design bureau and built in the USSR from May 1955. The aircraft was the largest and fastest passenger plane at that time and also had the longest range (10,900 km (6,800 mi)).  It has held the official title of fastest propeller-driven aircraft since 1960.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev116">The Tupolev Tu-116 (Russian: Tyполев Тy-116) is a turboprop-powered long-range airliner designed by the Tupolev design bureau and built in the USSR.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev124">The Tupolev Tu-124 (NATO reporting name: Cookpot) was a 56-passenger short-range twinjet airliner built in the Soviet Union.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev126">The Tupolev Tu-126 (NATO reporting name: Moss) was an airborne early warning and control aircraft developed from the Tupolev Tu-114 airliner by the Tupolev design bureau. It was in service with the armed forces of the Soviet Union from 1965 to 1984.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev128">The Tupolev Tu-28 (NATO reporting name Fiddler) was a long-range interceptor aircraft introduced by the Soviet Union in the 1960s. The official designation was Tu-128, but this designation was less commonly used in the West. It was the largest and heaviest fighter ever in service.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev134">The Tupolev Tu-134 (NATO reporting name: Crusty) is a twin-engine, narrow-body, jet airliner built in the Soviet Union from 1966 to 1989. The original version featured a glazed-nose design and, like certain other Russian airliners (including its sister model the Tu-154), it can operate from unpaved airfields.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev14">The Tupolev Tu-14  (NATO reporting name: Bosun)  (USAF/DOD reporting name: Type 35)  was a Soviet twin-turbojet light bomber derived from the Tupolev Tu-73, the failed competitor to the Ilyushin Il-28 \'Beagle\'.  It was used as a torpedo bomber by the mine-torpedo regiments of Soviet Naval Aviation between 1952–59 and exported to the People\'s Republic of China.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev142">The Tupolev Tu-142 (Russian: Туполев Ту-142) (NATO reporting name: Bear F/J) is a maritime reconnaissance and anti-submarine warfare (ASW) aircraft derived from the Tu-95 turboprop strategic bomber.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev144">The Tupolev Tu-144 (Russian: Tyполев Ту-144) (NATO reporting name: Charger) is a retired jet airliner and commercial supersonic transport aircraft (SST). It is one of only two SSTs to enter commercial service, the other being the Anglo-French Concorde. The design was a product of the Tupolev design bureau, headed by Alexei Tupolev, of the Soviet Union and manufactured by the Voronezh Aircraft Production Association in Voronezh, Russia.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev154">The Tupolev Tu-154 (Russian: Tyполев Ту-154) (NATO reporting name: Careless) is a three-engine medium-range narrow-body airliner designed in the mid-1960s and manufactured by Tupolev.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev155">The Tupolev Tu-155 is a modified Tu-154 (СССР-85035) which was used as an alternative fuel testbed. This is the first experimental aircraft in the world operating on liquid hydrogen. The similar Tu-156 was never built.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev16">The Tupolev Tu-16 (NATO reporting name: Badger) was a twin-engined jet strategic heavy bomber used by the Soviet Union. It has flown for more than 60 years, and the Chinese license-built Xian H-6 remains in service with the People\'s Liberation Army Air Force.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev160">The Tupolev Tu-160 (Russian: Туполев Ту-160 Белый лебедь) (NATO reporting name: Blackjack) is a supersonic, variable-sweep wing heavy strategic bomber designed by the Tupolev Design Bureau in the Soviet Union</string>
    <string name="Tupolev2">The Tupolev Tu-2 -development names ANT-58 and 103- -NATO reporting name Bat- was a twin-engine Soviet high-speed daylight and frontline (SDB and FB) bomber aircraft of World War II vintage.  The Tu-2 was tailored to meet a requirement for a high-speed bomber or dive-bomber, with a large internal bombload, and speed similar to that of a single-seat fighter. Designed to challenge the German Junkers Ju 88, the Tu-2 proved comparable, and was produced in torpedo, interceptor and reconnaissance versions. The Tu-2 was one of the outstanding combat aircraft of World War II and it played a key role in the Red Army\'s final offensives.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev20">The Tupolev Tu-95 -Russian: Туполев Ту-95- -NATO reporting name: Bear- is a large, four-engine turboprop-powered strategic bomber and missile platform. First flown in 1952, the Tu-95 entered service with the Soviet Union in 1956 and is expected to serve the Russian Air Force until at least 2040. A development of the bomber for maritime patrol is designated Tu-142, while a passenger airliner derivative was called Tu-114.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev214">The Tupolev Tu-214 (Russian: Туполев Ту-214) is a twin-engined medium-range jet airliner capable of carrying 210 passengers, designed by Tupolevand produced by Aviator SP and Kazan Aircraft Production Association.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev22">The Tupolev Tu-22 (NATO reporting name: Blinder) was the first supersonic bomber to enter production in the Soviet Union. Manufactured by Tupolev, the Tu-22 entered service with the Soviet military in the 1960s. The last examples were retired during the 1990s.Tu-22s were sold to other nations, including Libya and Iraq. The Tu-22 was one of the few Soviet bombers to see combat; Libyan Tu-22s were used against Tanzania and Chad, and Iraqi Tu-22s were used during the Iran–Iraq War.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev22m">The Tupolev Tu-22M -Russian-Туполев Ту-22М NATO reporting name: Backfire is a supersonic, variable-sweep wing, long-range strategic and maritime strike bomber developed by the Tupolev Design Bureau. According to some sources, the bomber was believed to be designated Tu-26 at one time.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev334">The Tupolev Tu-334 (Russian: Туполев Ту-334) was a Russian short-to-medium range airliner project that was developed to replace the ageing Tu-134s and Yak-42s in service around the world. The airframe was based on a shortened Tu-204 fuselage and a scaled-down version of that aircraft\'s wing.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev4">The Tupolev Tu-4 (NATO reporting name: Bull) was a piston-engine Soviet strategic bomber that served the Soviet Air Force from the late 1940s to mid-1960s. It was a reverse-engineered copy of the American-made Boeing B-29 Super fortress.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev70">The Tupolev Tu-70 (NATO reporting name: Cart) was a Soviet passenger variant of the Tu-4 bomber *which was a reverse-engineered copy of the American-made Boeing B-29 Super fortress* designed immediately after the end of World War II. It used a number of components from Boeing B-29s that had made emergency landings in the Soviet Union after running out of fuel after bombing Japan.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev75">The Tupolev Tu-75 was a military transport variant of the Tu-4 bomber, as was a similar airliner, the Tu-70, both using a new, purpose-designed fuselage. The first Soviet military machine of this class, it was equipped with a rear fuselage loading ramp.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev8">The Tupolev Tu-8 was a long-range variant of the Soviet Tupolev Tu-2 medium bomber that first flew after the end of World War II. It was canceled when it proved to be unstable, structurally unsound and its generators were not strong enough to fully power its gun turrets. With the advent of jet-powered bombers, Soviet military planners decided that it simply was not worth devoting the necessary resources to fix its numerous problems.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev80">The Tupolev Tu-80 was a Soviet prototype for a longer-ranged version of the Tupolev Tu-4 bomber, built after World War II. It was canceled in 1949 in favor of the Tupolev Tu-85 program which offered even more range. The sole prototype was used in various test programs before finally being used as a target.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev85">The Tupolev Tu-85 -USAF/DoD reporting name \'Type 31\'- NATO reporting name \'Barge\' was a Soviet prototype strategic bomber based on the Tu-4, an unlicensed reverse engineered copy of the Boeing B-29 Super fortress.</string>
    <string name="Tupolev95lal">The Tupolev Tu-95LAL -Letayushchaya Atomnaya Laboratoriya-literally: flying atomic laboratory was an experimental aircraft that was a modified Tupolev Tu-95 Soviet bomber aircraft, which flew from 1961 to 1965, analogous to the United States earlier Convair NB-36H Crusader.</string>


    <string-array name="slide_titles">
        <item>@string/slide_1_title</item>
        <item>@string/slide_2_title</item>
        <item>@string/slide_3_title</item>
        <item>@string/slide_4_title</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="slide_descriptions">
        <item>@string/slide_1_desc</item>
        <item>@string/slide_2_desc</item>
        <item>@string/slide_3_desc</item>
        <item>@string/slide_4_desc</item>
    </string-array>


</resources>
